Artem Timofeev

Contact

LinkedIn: Artem Timofeev

E-mail: atimofeev@tuta.io

Phone: +9 955 551114058

Github: https://github.com/atimofeev

8+ years of experience in supporting and engineering roles within fintech company. I was working with highly loaded and highly available complex trading systems.

Particularly enjoying automating routine tasks and reducing manual involvement in processes. I love learning and trying new things.

Currently using various AI tools on daily basis for increased productivity and problem solving.

Employment

Devexperts

DevOps Engineer

May 2021 — Apr 2023 Tbilisi, Georgia

- Linux systems administration and automation:
 - Production platforms troubleshooting
 - 24/7 critical incidents resolution
 - Configuration management (Git, BitBucket)
 - Regular deployments and monitoring setup for specific scenarios (TeamCity, Ansible)
 - Automation of support and maintenance operations (Ansible, Bash)
 - Scaling and maintenance of existing systems (Terraform, Consul, Nomad, Pacemaker)
 - Cisco ASA firewall rules configuration
 - Configuration of webservers/proxies (nginx, HAproxy, envoy)

Dec 2014 — May 2021 Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Tecnhical Support Specialist

- B2B customer support for complex trading systems and other financial solutions for top brokers, which includes:
 - Production platforms monitoring (Zabbix, Grafana, custom internal monitoring services)
 - Incident management and issue escalation (Jira, Slack, IP Telephony)
 - Communication with business clients, who have first line customer support on their side
 - Java application logs analysis for incident resolution
 - Bash scripting for small tasks automation
 - Regular manual QA checks on Prod and Staging platforms
 - Frequent SQL query writing for collection of various data from DB (PostgreSQL)
 - Writing technical documentation for existing and new processes, expanding common KB (Confluence)
 - Mentoring of new specialists and knowledge sharing

Education

2010 - 2014

Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnic University, Software engineering for computers and computer-based systems, Specialist

Additional education: English language in scope of professional technical communication

Used Tools

Version Control: GitHub, Bitbucket, Gitlab, Subversion

Programming Languages: Python, Bash, JavaScript

Monitoring: Zabbix, ELK stack, Grafana, Prometheus

Infrastructure/Configuration: Terraform, Ansible

Containerization/Orchestration: Docker, Nomad, Kubernetes

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Amazon RDS

CI/CD Tools: TeamCity, GitHub Actions, Gitlab CI/CD, Jenkins

Cloud Platforms: AWS

Other

Languages: advanced English, native Russian

Hobbies:

• Music creation: digital modular synthesizers for generative ambient and noise

• Making DYI projects: electronics, 3D modeling and printing, including custom self developed processes automation (jinja2, GCODE)

• Moutain biking: 10 years of experience in Downhill, Enduro, Pump Track and BMX racing

• Hiking in the mountains